Stanislaw M. Ulam Papers 1916-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.54
American Philosophical Society
- Series XV. Miscellaneous reprints, manuscripts, and journals, 1938-1986, 1.5 Linear feet 3 boxes
  - Graph reconstruction-a survey, n.d.; Bondy, J. A. (Box Series XV-1)
    See Series I: Kelly, Paul #4
  - Lectures on the theory of shape, 1974; Borsuk, Karol (Box Series XV-1)
  - Flight testing a nuclear rocket engine, n.d.; Boyer, Keith [?] (Box Series XV-1)
  - On a class of minimum-maximum problems, n.d.; Carter, David S. (Box Series XV-1)
    See Series IX: A collection of mathematical problems
  - Chess, 1960 (Box Series XV-1)
    Magazine
  - 17 Aug. 1973, Budrewicz, Olgierd (Box Series XV-1)
    In Polish; Perspektywy, no. 33 (207)
  - Nasi miedzy oceanami, 20 July 1973; Budrewicz, Olgierd (Box Series XV-1)
    In Polish; Perspektywy, no. 29 (203)
  - Scientists, decision-makers, and H-bombs: a cautionary tale,1949-1954, March 1982; Bundy, McGeorge (Box Series XV-1)
    From Series IV: H-bomb Conference, Princeton [21-23 June 1982]
  - Obiter dicta ex cathedra, 1 Dec. 1958; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974 (Box Series XV-1)
    Sports Illus., vol. 9, no. 22
  - On a problem of Ulam concerning families of measures of the unit interval, n.d.; Carlson, Tim (Box Series XV-1)
  - [On problem 94 of the Scottish Book], [1979?]; Chung, K[ai] L[ai] (Box Series XV-1)
  - Dr. Edward Teller's magnificent obsession, 6 Sept. 1954; Coughlan, Robert (Box Series XV-1)
    Life, vol. 37, no. 10
  - On a new method to solve in the large some nonlinear differential equations using high speed digital computers, 1956; De Vogelaere, Rene (Box Series XV-1)
  - [Review of Ulam's "A collection of mathematical problems], 1961; Dieudonne, J. (Box Series XV-1)
  - 5 July 1976, In German; SMU pp. 130-131; Der Spiegel, Nr. 28 (Box Series XV-1)
  - The death of a project, 9 July 1965; Dyson, Freeman J. (Box Series XV-1)
    Project ORION; Science, vol. 149, no. 3680
  - The hydrogen-bomb decision: a reappraisal, 20 Aug. 1976; Dyson, Freeman J. (Box Series XV-1)
    Science, vol. 193, no. 1976
  - Cell-adhesion molecules: a molecular basis for animal form, n.d.; Edelman, Gerald M. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Scientific man for all seasons, 10 Mar. 1968; Edson, Lee (Box Series XV-2)
    NY Times
  - Some problems and results in combinatorial set theory, 1961; Erdös, Paul, 1913-1996 (Box Series XV-2)
    lecture
  - Mechanical resonance dispersion in metals at audio frequencies, 1957; Fitzgerald, Edwin R. (Box Series XV-2)
    reprint
  - Mechanical resonance dispersion in quartz at audio-frequencies, n.d.; Fitzgerald, Edwin R. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Matrix inversion by a Monte Carlo method, 1950; Forsythe, George E. and Richard A. Leibler (Box Series XV-2)
  - On a problem of S. Ulam, 1971; Fournier, Gilles (Box Series XV-2)
  - Distribution of numbers and distribution of significant figures, 13 Jan. 1945; Furry, W. H. and Henry Hurwitz (Box Series XV-2)
    Nature
  - The man who invented the H-bomb: Adventures of a Mathematician, 9 May 1976; Gardner, Martin, 1914-2010 (Box Series XV-2)
    NY Times book review
  - Mathematical games, n.d.; Gardner, Martin, 1914-2010 (Box Series XV-2)
  - On the complex system of man and machine, 1957; Gelernter, H. L. (Box Series XV-2)
  - [Review of Ulam's "A collection of mathematical problems"], 1961; Gelernter, H. L. and B. B. Mandelbrot (Box Series XV-2)
  - Mathematics and logic, Goodstein, R. L. (Box Series XV-2)
    Review
  - On a certain sequence which converges to the generalized transfinite diameter of a plane set, [1957?]; Gorski, J. (Box Series XV-2)
    Author's summary
  - On Ulam's problem on families of measures, 1978; Grzegorek, E. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Official register, 1940; Harvard University. (Box Series XV-2)
    vol. XXXVII, no. 7
  - Measures and set theory, Oct. 1968; Hewitt, Edwin (Box Series XV-2)
    Reprint of review of SMU's film
  - Sur des theorèmes de Borsuk-Ulam et de Knaster, 1944; Hirsch, Guy (Box Series XV-2)
  - A continuous version of the Borsuk-Ulam theorem, 1981; Jaworowski, Jan (Box Series XV-2)
  - A history-dependent random sequence defined by Ulam, 1969; Kac, M[ark?] (Box Series XV-2)
  - Matematyka, jej kierunki i napiecia, 1963; Kac, Mark (Box Series XV-2)
    in Polish
  - Mathematics and logic, March, 1970; Kemeny, J. G. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Mathematics and logic: retrospect and prospects, [1968?]; Kneebone, G. T. (Box Series XV-2)
  - The end of elegance: the computer invades mathematics, May/June 1977; Kolata, Gina Bari (Box Series XV-2)
    Science, vol. 17, no. 3
  - Problem 24 of the Scottish Book, n.d.; Labuda, Iwo and R. Daniel Mauldin (Box Series XV-2)
  - H-bomb scientist, Mar. 1959; Lowell, Steve (Box Series XV-2)
    New Mexico,vol. 37, no. 3
  - The number of classes of subsets of a finite set with indistinguishable elements, Lynch, James (Box Series XV-2)
  - Maintenance, assembly and disassembly building for Project ROVER (Box Series XV-2)
  - The solution of one of Ulam's concerning analytic rectangles, n.d.; Mansfield, R. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Science and defense policy, Apr. 1977; Marsh, Jeffrey (Box Series XV-2)
  - Our atomic world, 1946; Marshak, Robert E., Elfred C. Nelson, and Leonard I Schiff (Box Series XV-2)
    Booklet written by LASL scientists
  - Mathematics, 1969; May, Kenneth O. (Box Series XV-2)
    Review of Math. and Logic
  - Mathematics and logic, 23 Jan. 1969; McElroy, Andy (Box Series XV-2)
  - Project ORION decision imminent, Oct/Nov 1962; McGuire, Frank G. (Box Series XV-2)
    Missiles and Rockets Magazine
  - [?]-forcing and problems of Ulam, Tarski, and Bing, [1976?]; Miller, Arnold W. (Box Series XV-2)
  - The collaboration between Oskar Morgenstern and John von Neumann on the theory of games, Sept. 1976; Morgenstern, Oskar (Box Series XV-2)
    J. Econ. Lit., 14, no. 3 (1976), 805-816
  - The H-bomb secret in St. Sauver, Joseph E., Thermonuclear weapon design and public literature, 1982; Morland, [?] (Box Series XV-2)
    Microfiche
  - Functions of self adjoint transformations as integrals, 1960; Mott, Thomas, E. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Some continuous Monte Carlo methods for the Direchlet problem, Sept. 1956; Muller, Mervin E. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Mathematics and logic, June 1969; Mullin, A. A. (Box Series XV-2)
  - [Review of Ulam's "A collection of mathematical problems"], 1960; Oxtoby, John C. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Ideals on the real line and Ulam's problem, Pelc, Andrzej (Box Series XV-2)
  - Sure une proprieté d'une classe de mésures abstraites, n.d.; Popruzenko, J. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Note sur le problème de Ulam, n.d.; Pouzet, Maurice (Box Series XV-2)
  - Quelques remarqes sur les resultats de tutte concernant 6 problèmes de Ulam, n.d.; Pouzet, Maurice (Box Series XV-2)
  - On the theory of types, 17 Mar. 1938; Quine, W. V., (Willard Van Orman) (Box Series XV-2)
  - Two questions of a sequence of S. M. Ulam, [1972?]; Recaman S., Bernardo (Box Series XV-2)
    Guy, Richard K.
  - Essays on the brain and education, 1985; Richtmyer, R. D. (Box Series XV-2)
  - Monte Carlo methods, 1959; Richtmyer, R. D. (Box Series XV-2)
    Talk
  - Sample styles for introduction to Stan Ulam's papers, [1970?]; Rota, Gian-Carlo, 1932-1999 (Box Series XV-2)
    Humorous
  - [Interview with Dr. Iwo Bialyniki-Birula], n.d.; Sawa, Bozena (Box Series XV-3)
    In Polish; transcript
  - Some elementary attempts at numerical modeling of problems concerning rates of evolutionary process, 1971; Schrandt, R. and S. Ulam (Box Series XV-3)
  - Pattern recognition in genetic sequences, 1979; Sellers, Peter H. (Box Series XV-3)
  - Now it should be told: who really invented the H-bomb, 23 Feb. 1964; Shearer, Lloyd (Box Series XV-3)
    San Diego Union "Parade Mag."
  - Error estimates for the [?] determination by the Monte Carlo method, n.d.; Siegert, A. J. F. (Box Series XV-3)
  - On the Vitali theorem, [1957?]; Sikorski, R. (Box Series XV-3)
  - AEC themonuclear weapons program chronology, n.d.; Smyth, Henry De Wolf, 1898-1986 (Box Series XV-3)
    From Series IV:H-bomb conference, Princeton